人类的一小步
One small step for man...
浪费你零花钱的一大步
One giant waste of your monthly allowance.
安全装置脱离
Safeties disengaged.
准备发射  五  四  三  二
We're go for launch in five, four, three, two,
一
one!
真是帅呆了
That was freakin' awesome!
天啊  不是吧
Aw, jeez. Come on.
我老爸一定饶不了我
My father's gonna kill me!
我能把这也拍下来吗
Can I film that too?
怎么了
What?
天呐
Oh, man...
那人死了吗
Is that guy dead?
我想是的
I think so.
去把其它的火苗扑灭
Get the rest of the flames out!
你  你没事吧  先生
You--you gonna be okay, mister?
闻起来像是
It smells like...
像是甘草味
like licorice.
你们觉得豪斯今天会来吗
Think House is coming in today?
如果我们开始提供SPA服务  他或许会来
Maybe if we start offering SPA treatments.
他都已经跳过一次酒店阳台了
He already jumped off of a hotel balcony.
天晓得接下来他会闹哪样
Who knows what he'll do next?
骑着野鸡战车来上班吗
Ride some kind of prostitute chariot to work?
提供我有趣病例的第一人
First person to offer me an interesting case
可以骑"她"
gets to ride her--
单飞或是双飞
single or double-team.
我是说我的小轮车
My scooter,
可一旦说出来
which, you know, said out loud,
听着反而更不对劲了
sounds even more inappropriate.
你不是吧  竟然带她们来上班了
Seriously? You're bringing them to work now?
二十三岁  流浪男性
23-year-old homeless man brought into the E.R.
因烧伤被送入急诊室
with burn injuries and--
让我猜猜  诊断结果是火烧的
Let me guess-- diagnosis was fire.
他说他被灼烧的皮肉闻着像甘草
He said his burning flesh smelled like licorice,
急诊室的防腐剂
and the E.R. antiseptics
闻起来像蓝莓松饼
like blueberry muffins.
酷
Cool.
嗅觉障碍  原因很杂
Dysosmia-- could be anything
从环境因素
from an environmental factor
到退行性脑病的早期症状都有可能
to an early sign of a degenerative brain disease.
你闻着像个赢家
Smells like a winner.
你和奇斯去他被发现的那个公园看看
Okay, you and Chase go check out the park where they found him.
你们两个给他用强的松
You two load him up with prednisone,
给他做个气味分辨测试
give him an odor I.D. test.
如果他依旧错把自己的体味当成是糖果
If he's still mistaking his body odors for candy,
那就绝对是脑部的问题了
the problem's definitely in his brain.
另外  找出他还撒了什么谎
Also, find out what else he's lying about...
因为我在想"弗勒斯·布勒"
Since I'm assuming "Ferris Bueller"
并不是他的真名
is not his real name.
为什么
Why?
说真的  那是谁
Seriously, who is that?
传说他是个正义使者
They say he's a righteous dude.
差点忘了  各位  见过多米尼卡
Before I forget, I want you to meet Dominika.
她就要成为
She's about to become
豪斯团队的一名永久成员了
a permanent member of team House.
很高兴见到大家
Nice to be meetings you all.
她具体要干些什么
Doing what exactly?
我
Me.
我们周五就要结婚了
We're getting married on Friday.
上来
Mount up!
我觉得这不该两个人一起骑
I don't think that two people are supposed--
生活很艰难呀  小宝贝
Living on the edge, baby doll!
胳膊怎么样了
How's the arm?
很疼
It hurts.
我现在就得出院了吗
Do I have to check out now?
等我们先弄清你的嗅觉为何会失常再说
Not until we figure out why your sense of smell is off.
你最先觉察到这点是在什么时候
When was the first time you noticed it?
大概是几个月之前
Maybe a couple months ago.
我们还需要知道你的真实姓名
We also need you to tell us your real name,
以便于我们回顾你的既往病史
so we can review your medical records.
不是我主动要求来这里的好吗
I didn't ask to come here, okay?
这一切我一分钱也不会付
I'm not paying for any of this.
别担心
Don't worry.
我想没有收帐公司
I don't think the collection agency
会在公园办公吧
has an office in the park.
我没有病史
I don't have a medical history.
我一直很健康
I've always been healthy.
那这些疤痕和烧痕是怎么回事
What about those scars and burn marks?
身体往前探点
Lean forward.
是我爸
My dad...
我小时候我们处得不太好
We didn't exactly get along when I was a kid.
你住过几次院
How many times were you hospitalized?
从来没有
Never.
他很在行
He was good at it.
总能确保他干的坏事
Made sure he never did anything
用一件运动衫就能盖住
that couldn't be covered up by a sweatshirt.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
别  没必要
No, don't be.
我一点不难过  过去就过去了
I'm not. The past is the past.
所以我不愿意谈及这些
That's why I don't like talking about it.
你不能在这里骑这玩意
You can't ride that thing in here.
说到玩意[事情]
Speaking of things,
我周五有件大事
I'm having one on Friday.
如果你打算顺便来访
If you want to drop by,
我们欢迎您的光临
we'd love to have you.
别有压力
No pressure.
你还站在上面呢
You're still standing on it.
是的
So I am.
或许你不是太熟悉
Perhaps you're not familiar
《新泽西州残疾人法案》
with New Jersey Handicap Ordinances.
或许我熟悉
Or perhaps I am.
法案只适用于轮椅和助动小轮车
They apply to wheelchairs and powered scooters only,
而不是玩具
not toys.
你可知道这个玩具价值几何
Have you any idea how much this toy cost?
我管不着
I don't care.
出于某种原因  本周我的腿疼得很厉害
For some reason, my leg's been hurting a lot this week.
出于某种原因  我还是管不着
For some reason, I still don't care.
好吧  我会把车退掉
Fine. I'll return it.
我是不是只能从这里步行推它出去了
Do I have to walk it out of here?
算了
Stop.
为了你的腿我就破例一次
I'll make an exception for your leg.
但下次  请先让我知道
But next time, check with me first.
恭贺新禧啊
Congratulations on your engagement.
我听到一个奇怪的声音
I hear a strange voice.
是个看起来很柔弱的人
A very soft-looking man.
一定是威尔森吧
Must be the Wilson.
我知道我们说过彼此间不留秘密
I know we said no secrets,
但这个人还是让我自己处理吧  宝贝
but I think I need to take this alone, honey bunny.
好吧
Okay.
很高兴见到你
Nice to be meeting you.
你是想利用卡迪
You're trying to screw with Cuddy.
是啊  这就是那狗血的"你甩了我
Yeah, it's the classic "You dumped me,
所以我就在一周后结婚"的桥段
so I'm gonna get married a week later" ruse.
因为这样就不单单是她很傻
'Cause not only is she that stupid,
而且很显然我也很傻
but apparently I'm that stupid.
然后呢  你就公开的嘲笑婚姻
Then what, you're openly mocking marriage--
来证明婚姻毫无意义
trying to prove it means nothing?
确实没有意义
It doesn't.
但却是你在N年前就已亲身验证了
But you proved that yourself years ago.
我很想继续陪你猜谜
I'd love to keep guessing,
但还有一群肿瘤病人等着我呢
but I've got people with tumors waiting.
为什么你想让我们认为你要结婚了
Why do you want us to think that you're getting married?
只剩下唯一的理论  我确实要结婚
Only one theory left-- I am.
多米尼卡需要绿卡
Dominika needs a green card.
所以你只是随便挑个陌生人帮一把
So you're just doing some random stranger a favor?
这是违法的  人们会因此锒铛入狱
It's illegal. People go to jail for that--
还得支付高额罚金
Pay huge fines.
你没见过我怎么行医的吗
Have you seen me practice medicine?
你知道雇名全陪女佣
You know how much it costs to have a live-in maid,
私人助理  厨师  按摩师和妓女要多钱吗
personal assistant, cook, massage therapist, whore?
我知道
I do.
她愿意一周免费为我工作四天
She's willing to work four days a week for free.
这能给我省下三万三千刀
It's gonna save me about $33,000.
我要做的就只是说那愚蠢的三个字
All I have to do is say two stupid words--
"我愿意"
"I do."
如果她不这么看呢
And if she doesn't see it this way?
我们订好了婚前协议  互不干涉
Iron-clad prenup--we go our separate ways.
你那震惊的表情按我理解就是在说
Your stunned look, I take it, is your way of saying,
"这主意实在是高  豪斯"
"Brilliant idea, House."
你看上去不一样了
Wow. You look different.
强的松经这段时间已经起作用了
The prednisone has had time to work,
现在需要你配合我们做个嗅觉测试
so we need to give you the odor I.D. test now.
没问题
Sure.
告诉我们你闻到了什么
We need you to tell us what you smell.
某些变质的东西
Something spoiled...
是腐肉吗
maybe rotting meat?
是婴儿爽身粉
It's baby powder.
我还挺喜欢这个的
I kind of like that one.
是薄荷吗
Peppermint?
是极其难闻的体臭
It's extremely bad body odor.
不得不承认
Well, you got to admit,
闻不到体臭对我来说是件好事
that one's kind of a good deal for me.
我的背包
My backpack.
你们在哪里找到的
Oh, where'd you find it?
公园  就在一堆不知道啥东西的旁边
In the park, right next to a big pile of questions.
你在注射什么毒品
What kind of drugs you shooting up?
维生素
Vitamin supplements.
我想增加自身的免疫力
I've been trying to boost my immune system.
好吧  如果你们不信就给我做检测
All right, test me if you don't believe me.
弗勒斯告诉你真名了吗
Ferris tell you his real name yet?
皮特·约翰逊
Peter Johnson.
丹尼·詹宁斯.
Danny Jennings.
那是我买的二手书
I bought those books used.
都是从同一个人那买的吗
All from the same guy?
不好意思  我想我还是现在就出院好了
I'm sorry, you know, I think I should check out now.
我该
And I should--ow!
怎么了
What's wrong?
我的胃
Oh, my stomach.
胃肠道出血
Gastrointestinal bleeding.
有人对这有意见吗
Is anyone else disturbed by this?
怎么了
What?
她主动要求的
She offered.
也许丹尼在真名这事上骗了我们
Danny may have lied about his name,
但对那些小瓶里的东西  他说的是实话
but he was telling the truth about the vials.
检测确认了那些是维生素A和B12
Tests confirm they were vitamin "A" and B12.
他还喜欢维生素H[指海洛因]
He also enjoys vitamin "H".
那小子是个瘾君子
The kid's a junkie.
毒理检测显示他没有使用毒品
Tox screens were negative for drug use.
他的头发不是  我拿去测试了
His hair wasn't. I had it tested...
因为不像圣诞老人和复活节兔子
'cause unlike Santa and the Easter Bunny,
无家可归  精神正常  二十出头
homeless, non-mentally ill 20-somethings
却不吸毒的生物是不存在的
without drug problems don't exist.
过去五个月内的某段时期他曾大量吸毒
He was a heavy user sometime in the last five months.
真是太爽了
That was incredible.
-谢谢  -不  谢谢你
- Thank you. - No, thank you.
我喜欢脚又大又厚又性感的男人
I like a man with the big, strong, sexy feet.
他还真把修手指甲理解成修脚趾甲了
He really puts the "Mani" in the "Pedi."
如果他吸食过海洛因
If he has a history of snorting heroin,
可能导致自身嗅觉障碍
he could have caused the dysosmia himself.
但我们还是得解释消化道出血的问题
But we still need to explain the bleeding in his G.I. tract.
注射维生素可能导致出血
Vitamin injections could have caused that--
维生素A过量中毒综合症
Hypervitaminosis "A" syndrome.
就是说不同症状间没有联系
So his symptoms aren't connected.
豪斯  你觉得这可能吗
House, you buying this?
一般情况下不可能
Not usually.
但这人长期睡在一摊狗屎上
But this guy's been sleeping on a bed of dog poop.
就算他的每个症状
I wouldn't be surprised if he's got
都有不同的病因我也不会奇怪
six different symptoms for six different reasons.
流血可能是由消化道梗阻引起的
The bleed could be caused by a G.I. obstruction.
维生素过量说的通  且便于治疗
Vitamin O.D. makes sense, and it's easier to treat.
给他补充维生素E和锌
Give him tocopherol and zinc supplements
中和多余的维生素A  如果我们是对的...
for the excess vitamin "A". If we're right...
他明天又可以流浪街头了
he could go homeless tomorrow.
如果我们错了
And if we're wrong,
他的肠道问题会更加严重
his intestines could get further distressed,
因为我们忽略了消化道梗阻的问题
while we ignore the G.I. obstruction.
你看当女人不用为了留在美国而伺候男人时
See what happens when women don't have to serve men
都会发生什么
to stay in the country?
她们就会自命不凡
They get all uppity.
这也是我们发明绿卡的原因
This is why we invented green cards.
给他的腹部拍个X光片
Go X-Ray the guy's abdomen,
如果这能让你心理平衡的话
if it'll make you feel all equal.
想请你帮个忙
I need a favor.
我想提前几天把我未婚妻的名字
I want to add my fiancee's name
加到我的医疗保险上
to my health insurance a few days early.
她想在大喜之日前镶个牙
She wants to get a tooth capped before the big day.
-我不会签的  -我同意
- I'm not signing this. - I agree.
我觉得她现在这样就很美了
I think she looks beautiful the way she is.
不  等等
Oh, no, wait.
你不签是出于道德原因吗
You're not signing that for moral reasons?
你是想当真爱的独裁者吗
You're declaring yourself the sole arbiter of true love?
因为你曾多年掩护陶博的妻子
'Cause you covered Taub's wife for years.
你这是欺诈
It's fraud.
她想让我贿赂你
She wanted me to bribe you,
就像在他们的国家那样
like they do back in the old country.
告诉她我说过什么
Tell her what I said.
这是美国
This is America--
勇敢者的自由家园
the land of the home and the free of the braves.
没错  每次听她这么说
Yeah, I just get teary-eyed
我都热泪盈眶
every time I hear her say that.
她给你带了份礼物
She brought you a gift.
杏仁蛋糕  我亲手做的
Almond kulich-- I make with own hands.
很美味的
I-it's delicious.
杏仁蛋糕  你怎么忍心拒绝呢
Almond kulich--how can you say no to that?
你知道如果我签了
You realize if I do sign this
而你们没有合法结婚
and you don't get legally married,
你会失去我们提供的所有保险
you'll lose your insurance with our carrier?
了解
Yes.
好吧
Fine.
你的生活你做主
It's your life.
我祝福你们
I wish you both the best with it.
谢谢
Thank you.
向北前进  黛丝犸克小姐
North, Miss Teschmacher!
你的血检没问题
Your blood test was clean,
但头发显示你曾吸过海洛因
but your hair showed heroin use.
我已经有三个月没再碰了
I've been clean over three months now.
你怎么戒的
How'd you kick it?
我先死过一次
I had to die first.
十一月时我服药过量
I O.D.'d back in November,
他们说临床来讲我死亡了几分钟
and they said I was clinically dead for several minutes.
感觉像是上帝给了我第二次机会
It was like God gave me a second chance
来做些正确的事
to do things right this time.
你是说是上帝治好你的吗
You're saying God cured you?
不  是州戒毒所治好了我
No. State Rehab cured me.
而我本应该死去  但我没有
But I should be dead, but I'm not.
这一定有什么特殊的意义
It has to mean something.
我会在这里一定是有原因的  对吧
I mean, I-I must be here for a reason, right?
那你知道是什么原因了吗
Did you figure out the reason?
我希望有朝一日能成为一名医生
My goal is to become a doctor one day.
我很聪明的
I am smart.
我高中毕业时得到了医科大学预科的奖学金
I mean, I got a scholarship for premed out of high school.
奇斯
Chase...
你看
Look.
我们发现他的结肠壁上散布着十三个肿块
We found 13 masses spread across the wall of his colon,
直径在两到八毫米之间
ranging from two to eight millimeters.
不可能是肿瘤  边缘太过光滑分明
It can't be tumors. Edges are too sharp and defined.
我以为那可能是寄生虫
I thought it might be parasites,
但在X光照射下  没有发现任何活动
but we didn't see any movement between x-ray exposures.
在他的粪便样本中也没有发现幼虫或虫卵
And no larvae or eggs were observed in any of his stool samples.
就一名住公园的流浪瘾君子来说
Which is kind of surprising
这倒是桩新鲜事
for a homeless junkie living in a park.
是前瘾君子
Ex-junkie--
他声称已有三个月没吸了
claims he's been clean for over three months.
而且他也打算结束流浪生活
And he's not planning on staying homeless.
他正努力保护自身健康
He's trying to protect his health,
所以才会补充维生素
which is why he's been taking vitamin supplements.
他想当医生
He wants to be a doctor.
他不过是了说些你爱听的
He's just telling you what you want to hear.
一旦上瘾  终生成瘾
Once an addict, always an addict.
你能
Can you...
不当着我的面这么做吗
please not do that in front of me?
估计很难
Doubt it.
你就是我嗑药的主要原因
You're the main reason I'm on the stuff.
我们现在所看到的也许是
We could be looking at fungal masses
附着在他结肠壁上的真菌肿块
hanging off the walls of his colon.
今晚先给他用两性霉素B
Start him on amphotericin "B" Tonight,
明天早上  给他做个结肠镜检查
And in the morning, run a scope up where the sun don't shine,
看能不能找到块菌
see if you can find any truffles.
我觉得我们应该捍卫原则  抵制这场婚礼
I think we should boycott this wedding on principle.
我估计必须得去
I kind of have to go.
他的未婚妻都给我脚底按摩了
His fiancee did give me a foot massage.
而且他也邀请我去参加他的婚宴了
And he invited me to be in his wedding party.
那奇斯呢  他邀请他了吗
W-what about Chase? He ask him?
-对  他也去  -活见鬼
- Yep. He's in it. - What the hell?
你刚还说你不会去的
You just said you weren't even going.
那我还是会伤心的啊
I still have feelings.
那是什么
What's that?
绝对不是真菌
That's definitely not a fungus.
你会出血  是因为在你的消化道里
You were bleeding because you had 13 pieces of bone
有十三片碎骨
in your digestive tract.
我们认为你有异食癖  由体内化合物失调
We think you have pica, a craving for nonfood items
导致对非食物的渴望
that's caused by a chemical imbalance--
我并不渴望它们  算是
I didn't crave them. I kind of...
志愿吞食它们的
volunteered to eat them.
什么  为什么
W-what? Why?
有家很棒的意大利餐厅
There's this great Italian restaurant
我经常光顾
I like to frequent.
我说的"餐厅"
And by "Restaurant",
是指餐厅后面的垃圾箱
I mean their dumpster out back.
那里的厨师算是我的朋友
The cook is kind of a friend of mine.
他向我挑战  让我尝试各类东西
He challenges me to eat stuff.
有时是生鱿鱼
Sometimes it's raw squid,
不然就只有鸡骨头了
or, you know, I have to chew on a chicken bone.
可一旦我照做了  他就会用真正的食物招待我
But if I do it, then he hooks me up with real food,
-而不只是些垃圾  -多"好"的朋友啊
- not just the garbage. - Great friend.
这些碎片本可能会
These fragments could have
刺穿你的结肠从而导致死亡
perforated your colon and killed you.
你必须答应我们你不会再这么做了
You have to promise us you'll stop.
我觉得我的眼睛不太对劲
I think there's something wrong with my eyes.
怎么了
What is it?
就像是我正从井底看着你们
Uh, it's like I'm looking at you from the bottom of a well.
如果我们给嗅觉障碍加上管状视野
If we add tunnel vision to the dysosmia,
就可以排除碎骨引起腹腔出血的可能
we can subtract the bone-induced abdominal bleeding.
我认为嗅觉障碍是海洛因引起的
I thought the dysosmia was from heroin.
他说他从不用鼻吸的方式  只用静脉注射
He said he never snorted. He just shot up.
所以那不会影响他的嗅觉
So that wouldn't have affected his sense of smell.
我们为什么要相信那个躺着的骗子呢
And we believe the lying liar why?
豪斯
House...
你在听我们说话吗
Are you even listening to us?
当你们肯定都有何症状并给出意见
I'll start when you decide what the symptoms are
我会听的
and give me some theories.
结合考虑嗅觉障碍和管状视野
If we combine the dysosmia with the tunnel vision,
符合西方马型脑炎的症状
the symptoms fit for western equine encephalitis.
但病人不符合  他没有发烧
But the patient doesn't-- no fever.
干嘛呢
What the hell?
负面强化
Negative reinforcement.
会不会是福斯特.肯尼迪综合征
What about Foster Kennedy syndrome?
他可能有脑膜瘤或者浆细胞瘤
He could have a meningioma or plasmacytoma.
最先压迫他的嗅神经
Started by pressing on his olfactory nerves,
影响他的嗅觉
it affects his sense of smell,
现在进一步发展  压迫到他的视神经了
and now it's growing and pressing on his optic nerve.
很好  给他做脑部核磁共振  找到肿瘤
Good. MRI his head, find it.
迅速影响了我们的社区
...have an immediate impact on our community.
我们可以延长时间
We could extend the hours--
-有什么问题吗  -没有
- Something wrong? - No.
我在想或许先参观下我们的门诊部
I just think maybe it would be a better idea to have a tour
会是个好主意
of the clinic first.
请走这边
It's right this way.
我们有几位患病儿童
We have several patients that are children,
我们认为
and we find that it's important
提供他们玩耍的机会
to give them the opportunity to play
好让医院显得不那么恐怖十分重要
to make the hospital a less intimidating place.
我爸爸以前常把我锁在衣橱里
M-my dad used to lock me in a closet,
这  我现在感觉快不能呼吸了
and it--and it feels like I can't breathe.
我们需要你保持不动
We need you to stay still.
让他喘口气
Give him a break.
你希望他乱动吗
You want him squirming around?
那样我们得再做一次
We'll have to do it twice.
我希望你能对他多点尊重
I want you to show him a little respect.
你真觉得这小子可以步入正轨吗
You really think this kid can turn his life around?
他相信上帝给了他第二次机会
He believes God gave him a second chance.
这种信仰很有力量
That kind of belief can be powerful.
马斯特斯倒没让我惊讶
Masters doesn't surprise me.
他耍了医学院学生
He plays the fellow med student
梦想成为医生的把戏  把她给绕进去了
who dreams of being a doctor and reels her in.
可你竟然相信他与上帝深深牵绊的鬼话吗
But you falling for his deep connection with God?
他心怀希望
He has hope.
在听说他遭遇的这一切后
After all he's been through,
让我想要支持他
it kind of makes me root for him.
我们甚至不知道他是谁
We don't even know who he is,
除了知道他骗我们他是别人
except that he lies about who he is.
说不定他那个嗜虐的父亲都是编出来的
The bit about his abusive father is probably all made up.
那伤疤也是弄假的吗
And he faked the scars?
他是个混混  可能卷入多起打架事件
He's a punk. Probably got into a lot of fights.
而他却利用那个父亲的故事博得你的同情
And he sucked you in using the dad story.
我觉得不太舒服
I don't think I'm feeling very well.
我觉得我要
I think I'm--
他吐了
He's vomiting.
都这样了  我该让他继续保持不动吗
Should I ask him to stay still while he does that?
他的顶叶皮层有两个黑点
He has two dark spots in the parietal cortex.
不是肿瘤
They're not tumors--
可能是什么损伤或是天生的缺陷
maybe some kind of, uh, injury or inborn defect.
很明显他曾因为吸毒过量
Apparently he was clinically dead
而临床死亡过数秒
for several seconds when he O.D.'d.
黑点可能是由于缺氧
The dark spots could be brain damage
造成的脑损伤
from oxygen starvation.
但并不是
Except it's not.
我曾经见过精神分裂症患者
I've seen MRI imagery like that
有这样的核磁共振表现
in schizophrenics.
三比二
Three serving two.
但是精神分裂症不能解释
But schizophrenia doesn't explain
他的血压暴涨
why his blood pressure skyrocketed,
以及在核磁共振室的呕吐
and he threw up in the MRI.
恐惧发作了  他有幽闭恐惧症
Panic attack. He's claustrophobic.
把他弄出来以后就没事了
He was fine once we let him out.
嗅觉障碍和管状视野可能是幻觉
The dysosmia and tunnel vision could be hallucinations.
除了  已经考虑到这点
Except, as was already covered,
之前在急诊室就排除了他患精神病的可能
he was screened for mental illness down in the E.R.
劈头盖头
In your head!
是"脸"
It's "Face."
劈脸盖脸
On your face!
很接近了
Close enough.
急诊室的医生漏掉了
The E.R. docs missed it,
因为那时他还没显现出主要的病症
because he didn't present with major symptoms yet.
我们正目睹它的萌芽阶段
We're seeing it in its infancy.
所以我们治疗他  然后呢
So we treat him, and then what?
他成了又一名无家可归的精神分裂症患者
He becomes just another schizophrenic homeless man
流浪街头  我们必须帮助他
wandering the streets-- we have to help him.
我也想啊  但我的名册上还有四百万疯子
I'd love to, but I got four million other crazy people
排在他前面等着我呢
ahead of him on my to-do list,
是真疯哦
along with milk.
你俩用了几个月的时间想找到一个
You two spent months trying to figure out a way to date
不影响彼此工作关系的交往方式
and not have it affect your working relationship.
现在你得因为分手做同样的事
Now you need to do the same thing for not dating.
我不需要
No, I don't.
我是认真的
This is serious.
你知道她
Did you know that she's--
她因甩了我快被内疚和自责淹没了
She's dying of guilt and feels horrible for dumping me.
这很好
It's great.
不是说她甩了我好
I mean, not the dumping part,
而是说我现在可以为所欲为了
but the part where she'll now let me do whatever I want.
所以你只是想惩罚她
So you're just trying to punish her?
她感觉对不起你
She feels bad,
而你唯一的目标就是利用这一点吗
and your only goal is to take advantage?
不对
That's not true.
我还有很多目标
I got plenty of goals.
其中一个就是
One of them is
在那里挂一台六十英寸的平板电视
a 60-inch flat screen right there.
你是多面人  豪斯
You're a lot of things, House,
但你从来不是个虐待狂
but you've never been a sadist.
你这是在殴打一个
You're pummeling an opponent
不会反击的对手
who isn't fighting back.
我已经给他上第二剂氯氮平了
I already gave him a second dose of clozapine.
-你不用再  -我赌
- You don't need-- - I'll bet
五十块他最喜欢的运动是曲棍球
you 50 bucks his favorite sport is hockey.
你怎么可能知道
How could you possibly know that?
直觉而已
Just a hunch.
你感觉如何
How you feeling?
我胳膊有点疼
My arm kind of hurts.
我会跟护士说增加你的止痛药剂量
I'll talk to the nurse about upping your pain meds.
曲棍球诶
Hockey, eh?
我侄子给我买的
Oh, my nephew bought it for me--
他知道我是个铁杆粉丝
knows I'm a huge fan.
我讨厌曲棍球
I hate hockey.
如果是精神分裂症  你将需要长期护理
If this is schizophrenia, you're gonna need regular care.
我找到几家
I found some shelters
有全职医护人员的疗养院  而且也有
that have full-time medical staff and also--
我胳膊很疼
Oh, my arm really hurts!
让我们看一下
Let's have a look.
感觉像着火了似的
It feels like it's on fire!
我们得揭开绷带看一下
We need to take a look under the bandages.
不不不  不是那只  是这只
Ow! No, no, no. Not that one, this one!
我的心肝们  快上车来
Ahoy there, me hearties! Permission to come aboard.
昨晚丹尼说他胳膊感觉像着火了似的
Danny said his left arm felt like it was on fire last night.
我们认为是精神分裂的幻觉  但
We assumed it was a schizophrenic delusion, but--
那不是幻觉  他在用氯氮平
It's not. He's on clozapine.
情况应该好转  而非更糟
He'd be getting better, not worse.
可能是区域疼痛综合征
Sounds like regional pain syndrome.
肯定是种遗传性疾病
Has to be a genetic disorder.
你能慢点么  你会害我们被抓的
Would you slow down! You're gonna get us arrested.
我不担心被抓
I wouldn't worry about it.
我们很可能会先挂
We'll probably die first.
别逼我脱鞋哦[进监狱时要脱鞋]
Don't make me take my shoe off!
我们得测试他的DNA
We need to run his DNA.
他可能有早发性帕金森病
He could have early onset of Parkinson's.
也可能是皮质基底节变性综合征
Or cortical-based ganglionic degeneration
或是亨廷顿氏病
or huntington's
或者几十种遗传性疾病中的任何一种
or any one of a dozen other genetic diseases.
如果你放我们出去
Hey, if you let us out,
我们就可以开始检查了
we can start testing.
如果全部检查一遍得花上几周时间
If we're gonna test for them all, it'll take weeks.
我才不要为了治这小子取消我的蜜月
I'm not canceling my honeymoon to treat this kid.
假结婚还要度真蜜月啊
It's a fake marriage, but a real honeymoon?
差不多吧
Most are.
丹尼也有可能
Danny could also die
死在我们检查完所有的可能性之前
before we get through testing for all the possibilities.
所以我们要走捷径
So we cheat.
既然是遗传病
Since it's genetic,
那他爹地或妈咪肯定也有
daddy or mommy's got it too.
他们不是病着就是死了
They're either sick or dead.
他不知道他母亲在哪里
He doesn't know where his mother is,
也不愿告诉我们他父亲在哪里
and he won't tell us where his father is.
他是个无家可归的前瘾君子
He's a homeless ex-junkie.
你是在告诉我你们四个天才都搞不定他一个吗
Are you telling me that you four geniuses can't outwit him?
绿灯
Green light!
卡迪给我弄的
Cuddy got it for me.
现在我正在起草一份
And now I'm drafting a request
关于由一台意式咖啡机与一把按摩椅
for a study into the effects of caffeine
引发的咖啡因效应之学术研究的申请
involving an italian espresso machine and a massage chair,
所以有话快说
so make it quick.
我找到丹尼的父亲了
I found Danny's father.
不错
Well done.
那孩子说他去年十一月
The kid said he was in
在一个政府资助的戒毒所戒毒
a state-sponsored rehab last November.
那段时间只有一个丹尼·詹宁斯
There's only one Danny Jennings
在那里接受治疗
that was in treatment at the time,
而且他在首要亲属栏里
and he listed his father's address
填了他父亲的地址
as his primary next of kin.
那句"不错"是想夸你挺快就说完了
The "Well done" was for making it quick.
现在我要收回那句话了
Now I'm gonna have to take that back.
他家离医院大概有三十分钟车程
He lives about 30 minutes from the hospital.
使你继续留在这里废话
And the reason you're continuing to talk
而不是开车去他家的原因是
instead of driving there?
奇斯和马斯特斯已经在路上了
Chase and Masters are already on their way.
你为什么没邀请我参加你的婚礼
Why didn't you ask me to be part of your wedding?
你因一个恶搞的婚礼被恶搞地鄙视
You are genuinely upset at being mockingly snubbed
而由衷得不安吗
by a mock wedding?
是因为我比他们在组里的时间短吗
Is it because I haven't been here as long as them?
还是因为你真的很不喜欢我
Or is it that you really don't like me?
还是你纯粹在耍
Or are-- are you just s-screwing--
我那个
I'll...
我等她弄完再回来吧
I'll come back when she's finished.
她弄完啦
She is.
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
你以为她在干什么
W-what did you think she was doing?
她只是在接有线电视
She's just installing the cable.
我可没打比方
That's not a euphemism!
我很同情这小矮个
Oh, I feel sorry for the little one.
有什么我们能做的吗
Isn't there something we can do?
有何贵干
Can I help you?
我们得和你谈谈你儿子丹尼的事
We need to talk to you about your son Danny.
丹尼  你们是谁
Danny? Who are you?
-我们是他的医生  -我们来了解一下
- We're his doctors. - We need to know if you,
你或他母亲
or perhaps his mother,
是否有任何家族遗传病史
have any family history of genetic disease.
怎么了  这有关系吗
Why? What difference would it make?
或许你不关心你儿子  但是
You may not care about your son, but--
丹尼戒毒期间
Is that what Danny told you
是这么和你们说的吗  说我们不爱他
when he was in rehab-- we didn't love him?
我们不是为这个来的
Um, not why we came here.
我们只是想知道
We just want to know
你家是否有确诊的遗传病史
if there's any diagnosed genetic disease in your family.
我们正在医治你儿子
We're trying to make your son better.
医治
Better?
他死于过量吸毒
He died of a drug overdose.
三个月前举行了葬礼
We buried him three months ago.
你是谁
Who are you?
你在干什么
Shh. What are you doing?
诊断
A test.
你到底是谁啊
Who are you?
重要的是  你是谁
The important question is, who are you?
丹尼·詹宁斯已经死了
Danny Jennings is dead,
就是说丹尼·詹宁斯没脉搏了
which means that Danny Jennings has no pulse.
然而  你
You, on the other hand...
尚有脉搏
do.
所以  你不是丹尼·詹宁斯
Ergo, you are not Danny Jennings.
要不就是我误诊了
Or I did the test wrong.
不如你就直截了当
So why don't you cut the crap
告诉我你的真名吧
and tell me your real name.
不
No.
掩饰身份
Hiding your identity--
那你不是罪犯就是超级英雄
Well, either you're a criminal or a superhero.
我不是罪犯
I'm not a criminal.
太帅了
Awesome.
我内裤是什么颜色的
What color is my underwear?
我是不会告诉你我的名字的
I'm not telling you my name.
好吧
No problem.
我只需要你父亲的名字
I just need your father's name.
省省吧
Forget it.
介意告诉我为什么吗
Care to tell me why?
他在找我
He's looking for me.
他大概
He supposedly...
已经戒了毒  戒了酒
cleaned up and got sober.
现在
And now he--
他想重新做回我父亲
he wants to be a part of my life again.
但我接受不了
And I can't let that happen.
现在你翅膀硬了
You're a big boy now.
还觉得他能伤害你吗
You still think he can hurt you?
你不懂
You don't get it.
如果我再见到他
If I ever see my dad again...
我一定会杀了他
I'll kill him.
我这是怎么了
What's happening to me?
算你走运
Well, luckily for you,
用不着你老爸就能把那弄明白了
we don't need daddy to figure that one out.
问出真名了吗
Did you find out his real name?
小脑共济失调
Cerebellar Ataxia.
好奇怪的名字
That's a weird name.
眼前的杯子  他抓空两次
The guy whiffed twice trying to pick up a cup
都没摸到
right in front of him.
加上其它症状
That plus everything else...
由此我们可以排除一些遗传病
Means that we have whittled our list of genetic diseases...
只剩一种
All the way down to one--
早发性帕金森病
Early-onset Parkinson's.
经历诸多不幸
After everything he's been through,
现在我们还得告诉他
now we have to tell him,
"嘿  你得了不治之症
"Hey, you have an incurable disease
只会日渐恶化"
that gets progressively worse."
你可以骗他  我是无所谓
You could lie. I'm fine with that.
给他用左旋多巴  同时做DNA测试确认
But you'll probably both feel better
那样可能你俩都会好过些
if you give him levodopa and confirm with DNA tests.
他太过分了
He's gone too far.
他那辆巨轮卡车占了
He's taking up six handicapped spaces
-六个残障停车位  -就四个
- with a monster truck. - It's only four,
结完婚他肯定就不要了
and he's gonna get rid of it after the wedding.
还有小教堂  他把小教堂
And the chapel-- he's turned the chapel
变成了他的私人宴客厅
into his own personal catering hall.
谁在乎
Who cares?
除了有一门卫在那里酒后打盹
Other than a janitor sleeping off a bender,
他是两周后第一个使用那地方的人
he's the first person to use it in two weeks.
面对赤裸裸的侵略
Appeasement is never the answer
姑息养奸绝不是解决之道
in the face of naked aggression.
不多久他的坦克就会
It won't be long before his tanks
开进你的香榭里舍大道[变本加厉]
are rolling down your champs-elysees.
我知道豪斯在做什么
I know what House is doing.
说起来  你有什么好在意的
You, on the other hand-- why do you care?
他又没伤到谁
He isn't hurting anyone.
你是第一个
You're the first boss he's ever had
能降住他的上司
who could handle him.
在你之前   他要么被炒鱿鱼
Before you, he was either fired
要么被无尽的医疗事故诉讼缠身
or buried under a mountain of malpractice suits.
他需要有人管着他
He needs someone to say no.
他需要能让他
He needs someone he'll listen to
服管的人
when they say no.
如果你真关心豪斯
If you really care about House,
别再为他感到抱歉
you'll stop feeling sorry for him
踏出这扇门  该怎么收拾他
and get out there and start kicking him
就怎么收拾他
where he needs kicking.
我改变主意了
I changed my mind.
怎么  你想用鱼肉换鸡肉吗
What, you want the fish instead of the chicken?
这房间是给病人家属用的
This room is for patients' families,
不是给想要欺诈政府的医生用的
not for doctors trying to defraud the government.
这么说来
Oh, so...
你决定遵从道德准则
You've decided to take a moral stand.
对
Yeah.
小教堂对某些人来说个可是神圣的地方
The chapel still has sanctity for some people.
说的对
You're right.
说来上周我看到那叫"布鲁"的门卫
In that case I saw Blue the janitor
在长凳上睡得不省人事
passed out in one of the pews last week.
是露  如果当时我在场也会赶他出去
It's "Lou" and I would have thrown him out too.
那我们要去哪里呢
Well, where are we gonna go?
我们说话这会儿承办酒席的正在楼下打点一切
We got caterers staging everything downstairs as we speak.
花艺陈列  餐具摆设
We've got floral arrangements, place settings...
还有其它结婚事宜
other wedding-y stuff.
那不是我的问题
That's not my problem.
我请帖都发了
I sent out the invitations.
客人正陆续赶来
People are coming here.
同样不是我的问题
That's also not my problem.
我还要收回电视
And I want the TV back.
直接让我死得了
You should just let me die.
没有我世界更美好
The world's better off without me.
很正常
It's normal.
听到坏消息人们都会沮丧
People feel depressed when they get bad news...
毕竟是坏消息
Because it's bad news...
很明显
Obviously.
我并不是偶然吸毒过量
I didn't O.D. by accident.
我是想自杀
I was trying to kill myself.
为什么
Why?
因为我做过很多
'cause I've done things...
可怕的事
horrible things.
我伤害过很多人
I've hurt people.
发现自己没死的时候
And when I didn't die,
我还以为
I thought...
我还以为上帝原谅了我
I thought God forgave me.
可他是要让我活着受苦
But he just wanted me to suffer.
我罪有应得
And I deserve it.
不
No.
你这不是罪有应得
You don't deserve it.
我
I...
我在大学里交过一个女朋友
I had a girlfriend in college...
我差点杀了她
And I almost killed her.
我失控了
I just snapped.
开始殴打她
And I started hitting her.
如果不是她室友碰巧回来
And if her roommate hadn't come home...
我有罪
I'm evil.
我跟我爸一样
I am just like my dad.
我们都是怪物  我该死
We're both monsters. I deserve to die.
我不能  不能
I can't... I can't...
我头晕
I feel dizzy.
这里需要急救车
I need a crash cart in here!
他心脏膨大  正在衰竭
His heart is dilated and failing.
照目前发展态势  他很快会需要心脏移植
And at the rate it's happening, he'll need a new one soon.
想让他上移植者名单门都没有
And there's no way we'll get him on the transplant list.
我们遗漏了什么
What are we missing?
什么都漏了  我们对这孩子一无所知
Everything. We know nothing about this kid.
只知道他入院以来病情不断恶化
Except that he's gotten worse since we admitted him.
为什么
Why?
大部分病人都是这样的
Most of our patients tend to do that,
除非被我们治愈
unless we cure them.
没错  但为什么如此之快
Yeah, but why so fast?
他嗅觉异常已经几个月了
He had dysosmia for a couple months,
从来没进医院治过
never even came here to get it treated.
不过是因为偶然烧伤入院
He's just a random burn victim.
我们一接诊
We get him,
就接二连三爆发管状视野
boom, he's got tunnel vision,
末梢多发性神经病变  小脑性共济失调
peripheral polyneuropathy, cerebellar ataxia,
现在又添了心肌病
and now cardiomyopathy.
医院到底有什么不一样呢
What's different here than, say, living
与肮脏的州立公园相比
in a filthy state park?
你认为是洁净让他生病的
You think cleanliness is making him sick?
过敏反应
Allergic reaction?
我们给他用了维科丁和氯氮平
We treated him with vicodin, clozapine,
静脉注射了一袋左旋多巴
and one I.V. bag of levodopa.
他的病情在那之前就开始恶化了
His condition started deteriorating before that.
拦住那个人
Stop that man!
我要看243号病人的食谱
I need the meal card for the patient in 243.
因为有了条件  他现在吃得健康了
He's eating healthy... because he can.
医院的伙食大部分是素菜
Most of the meals in here are vegetarian.
成人雷夫叙姆病
Adult refsum disease...
所有症状都吻合
fits all the symptoms.
他的机体内无法代谢食物中的植烷酸和叶绿素
His body can't process the phytanic acid and chlorophyll.
正是这些绿色蔬果组成的健康食谱
It's his healthy diet of green vegetables
要取他的性命
that's killing him.
-所以我们只要换食谱  -就能救他一命
- So if we change his diet... - We save his life.
给他用血浆去除治疗
Run him through a plasmapheresis treatment
去除他血液中的植烷酸
to remove the excess phytanic acid from his blood.
做基因检测确诊
Confirm with gene testing.
好啦  我得去结婚了
Okay, I got to go get married.
有人说真爱已不复存在
They say true love doesn't exist anymore.
或许压根就没存在过
Maybe it never did.
那么我们闲话少说
So without further ado...
多米尼卡·佩特洛娃  你愿意接受这个男人
Do you, Dominika Patrova, take this man
作为你的合法丈夫吗
to be your lawfully wedded husband?
我愿意
I do.
格利高里·豪斯  你愿意接受这个女人
And do you, Gregory House, take this woman
作为你的合法妻子吗
to be your lawfully wedded wife?
成
Yep.
依据新泽西州
Then by the power vested in me
今日暂时赋予我的权力
by the state of New Jersey just for today,
我宣布你们结为夫妻
I now pronounce you man and wife.
你可以亲吻新娘了
You may kiss the bride.
带相机的诸位  尽管拍别客气
Those of you with cameras, please feel free
留作法律文件证据
to provide legal documentation.
我没事  我只是气我自己
It's okay. I'm just angry at myself.
说好不让这事影响到我
I promised I wouldn't let this get to me.
还是被影响了
But it got to me.
只要你一句话
Just say the word,
我立刻陪你跳窗走人
and we will climb out that window right now.
我才不要让豪斯满意
I wouldn't give House the satisfaction.
你看到没
You see?
一切开始恢复正常了
Things are getting back to normal.
是啊
Yeah...
正常
Normal.
感觉好些了吗
Are you feeling better?
只要我注意摄入的食物种类
So all I have to do is eat the right kinds of food,
就没事了吗
and I'll be okay?
基本上  是的
Basically, yeah.
限制很严格
It's pretty limiting,
而且你终生都要控制
and it is for the rest of your life.
但只要你遵照食谱  定期检查
But if you follow the diet and get checked up regularly,
应该不会有事的
you should be fine.
谢谢你
Thank you...
没有放弃我
for not giving up on me.
你不是坏人
You're not a bad person.
你犯过错  可是谁没有呢
You made mistakes, but we all do.
等你出院之后  或许可以
Maybe when you get out of here, you can...
找人谈谈
go talk to someone...
-专业人士  -好
- A professional. - Yeah.
你提过的几个地方有专业人士
Yeah, some of those places you suggested had people on staff.
知道吗  我想上帝的确有重任交付于我
You know, I think God really does have a plan for me.
而这些  只不过是在考验我的信念
And all this... it was just his way of testing my resolve.
多亏有你  我才能通过考验
And I wouldn't have passed it without you.
明天见  丹尼
See you tomorrow, Danny.
那不是我的真名
That's not my real name.
无所谓啦
It doesn't matter.
我知道我们不是真结婚
I know this is not real marriage...
但我真的喜欢你
But I really like you.
我也喜欢你
I like you too.
不行
I can't.
为什么
Why not?
我从不跟有夫之妇上床
I never sleep with married women.
我要上床睡了
I'm going to bed.
你睡沙发吧
You can take the couch.
怎么回事
What's going on?
丹尼消失了  也没办出院手续
Danny disappeared without checking out.
所以你们就找联调局来了吗
So you called the FBI?
我们没找  他们自己来了
We didn't call them, they just showed up.
实验室检测丹尼DNA的时候
Danny's DNA... when we sent it to the lab for testing,
全国的警报都响了
it set off alarm bells all over the country.
什么警报
Alarm bells for what?
他涉嫌十三起未侦破谋杀案
He's linked to 13 unsolved murders
作案范围跨十个州
in ten different states.
他是连环杀手  还吃被害人尸体
He's a serial killer who eats his victims.
而我们救活了他
And we saved him.